If you haven't taken health insurance yet,
or you're planning to take health insurance,
and you're confused about which
companies offer these, but
which one is right for you, then
you must watch this video. This is our first
video about lemon juice and water. If
you've seen it, you'll understand that
investment and financial emergencies are
linked, but before investing,
you have to pay for your
financial emergencies. For this, one of them
is health insurance. God forbid, if
someone in your family falls ill and has to be
hospitalized, their
medical bills shouldn't be borne by you.
And you're studying for that pregnancy.
Before planning for investment,
educate yourself. For emergencies,
we've already explained where to find our settings
and how to pay for them. For this,
you should watch my first
video. You'll find it with juice and water. So,
let's have a look at this video.
[Music]
Hello, I'm Vishal, and you're watching
my channel, Soch Saadh Ke. Here we talk about
finance and investment.  Let's
think about the complexities in simple language. Today in this video we will
talk about
what are the benefits of health insurance. A health
institute is necessary for us,
what things should we check before that and which
insurance is suitable for us. When we
talk about health policy, then it is of two
types, one is individual
policy which you can write yourself, one is for a single 65
percent, second is family floater
family doctor, that is, and in your family there are
four members, husband, wife and two
children, then you have the same bill for all of them, for example,
5 lakh for you, so
if two members of your family fall ill within a year,
whose separate bills are of 2
or 2 lakh, then you will get ₹40 claim
from this health insurance company and
children can use one area of ​​​​now and news on the third number of job,
so let's start first,
why should we take it this year,
why is it necessary, as I
told in my video that if someone in our family falls ill
and the medical expenses in today's date have
increased a lot.  So, to
present that medical bill, you have to
spend money from your pocket and our
purpose of removing finance or finance
investment is everywhere,
if we do not have that 19 ways installed then we will have to
stop our goal and pay that money for the medical
bill.
Secondly, if you have taken Medical Treatment Plus,
then if you have this reference then you can
pay it, if you do
not have it installed then you would like it to be at a
lower cost, we can get a comment on the scrap.
Thirdly, in this you
get tax rebate from Monetary Fund
under section 80C, so in health insurance, the first
question that comes is how much amount of
cover should we take, its basic role is
that the average heart surgery cost in your situation or in your city,
you should take that much
health cover and that is why I take a family policy for my family which is
around Rs. 7.5 lakh nowadays in metro cities or as I talked about
emergency fund which should be your six months
salary,
but one point to note is that
whenever you take a family floater policy then
His Prem Mishra is
decided that he is the
most HKH member in the family, so it would be better if
you keep your parents on that floater
policy, keep their position and it will
stick to you in your next policy. The second
point is mostly policies. In this,
you are allowed room rent of only one percent of your luggage, that is,
whenever you fall sick
and you sleep in that room, then the data charges of the room you get will be only
1% of your policy limit.
If you take a bigger form than that, for example,
your SMS is of Rs. 5 lakh, then you are
awarded Rs. 5,000. If when you are nearby, there
is no vacant room for Rs. 5,000 and I call
you, then you will think that okay,
we will pay Rs. 2000 above Rs. 5,000 along with the
rest of the charges, we will get the payment at a lower rate,
but it happens that we complete the
capping of your room rent along with the
link of subsequent charges.  There are
surgery charges, doctor's fees,
stomach charges, medicine etc. So,
in all these things,
you will have to pay a percentage amount, which
is not right because we do PM on
which if we get sick, then we have to pay
hospital expenses on body system.
Now if we have given a room at a very high price and have limited it, then
we should do this. We have not
yet issued any rule on this, IRD does not know why it has
not come and you do not know this, if you have a
question then you have to check yourself
what is the room rent limit in it and it would be better if
you have a hospital there,
go there and check what is its charge in the hospital where you want to stay
and how much is
it expected to increase after the next five years, then
you can understand the answer according to your own. Now the
question is, which company should you choose for
taking health care
because as you search on Google, there will be many
companies which will provide all the policies.
Now what will you think that the
cheapest one is good, but making such a mistake,
tell me what does your company do that our
company  The claim settlement ratio is 99% and the
quantum further, within this, the claim encouragement, you to know about, is
90%. Let me tell you that claim
settlement ratio and claim in this are
two different things. Claim settlement
ratio means if a company has
100 crores of my and SIM not claims
approved within the whole year, then its claim is HD, if the
claim in this is a little right time,
what happens in this is that if a company has
collected a premium of 100 crores within the whole year, but its claim repacking is
90 crores, then its claim in this is
70%, that is, the money collected from it and the
money which is left after repairing it is
its profit, so if this cream of these
Congressmen is hundred percent,
it means the company is doing circuit cameras
and its condition is bad because it does
not have anything to match the company, then that is
also not good, if the claim of the company is for
inverter AC but it is 50%, it means out of
10  If five claims are rejected then it is
not good, so there is an industry
evidence that 70 to 90% of those whose premium is given by them,
you can use it. The next
point to check is that
in many companies there is a small cap but
you must pay attention to it that
if there is a cap like policy then do not take it because
whenever you get hospitalized, the cap that will be
provided to you will have many
rolls in that cap packet and you will have to
pay 20% for each item, so we are
doing this on premiums so that we do not have to
pay anything from our pocket, so it is better that
you do not take this cap option. The next thing to be noted is
very important, it is
useful in policies nowadays, it is called top up
super drip. Many times there is a question that some people have
reached for cheap sugar, so they
keep their understanding low and the treatment is that this cap is
not sufficient for them, they should
increase it, so what role does
top up play here and
many people know that
some sider of top up top up is your additional benefit.
Exit Poll Sikandar, this is an Individuals End
Policy, so you can get it from any company or
any other company, it is not necessary
that you have to take that top up from the same company from which you took
your base poll, I would request you
never to take top up without thinking, always take super top up.
Why am I saying this, first the problem should be solved,
for example, if your base spoilt
is 5 lakhs and you have taken another top up of
5 lakhs, then your total arm hole is that
of 10 lakhs, for example, if there is
any impact in your family and its bill comes
and 1 lakh rupees, then 5 lakhs from your side
and 3 lakhs from Play Store will be paid on your bill
as if nothing will be lost for you, but
if within the same year any other member goes to
hospital and his bill also comes
₹2, you will feel that you still have one
top up left, you
can do it from that, if it is not so, then the top up gets
activated only when your base is over, that is,
your base limit will be reached,
if your  The topper gets activated only when the bill comes above 5 lakhs, otherwise it will
not happen,
but this time your heart is set on Chittorgarh
Top and it is decided that first
you will either deposit 5 lakhs in your account or deposit your first
bet, when this gap is over
then I will come to know that I have to
back it up and suppose your bill is
more, that is, you have received 7
lakhs which is more than 5 lakhs, if your
base amount has already been ABS within the year then
you will have to pay that
first 5 lakhs, after that 2 lakhs will go from your top up,
so this is the topic of taking top up
and let us understand the super top up, now let us take a
sample from inside the super top box as well,
for example, the bet is 5 lakhs, your
top is 5 lakhs and the total is up to now, your claim
comes to 7 lakhs, so out of the first seven people,
five have been taken, out of which a little further ahead,
like you did not do anything from Superman, then another one
comes for you which is 3 lakhs, so
you will get three rupees inside the super top up,
in this one more  The point is that
you should always do top up and super top up from the same company
from which you have your best policy because
if you have a best policy from some other company
and you top up with some other company
and if your bill is above the best policy
then first of all the claim will
go to you but the remaining money will have to be paid by you
then you set up its bill in the
other company after that you
get its mention and in that communication there is a
lot of documentation process to pay the computer company bill
which is very
tasty, its treatment is done by other people if you take top up or
super top up then the same company has only one more
point this is called restoration
benefit for example if your policy is of
5 lakhs and you have used
4 lakhs for one number then now you have to worry about 1 lakh remaining so
many companies give this benefit, if
you have used the amount for any of these then the
balance will be refunded so you
can get back the 5 lakhs taken from you and some
companies do it while some have a warning
that they will not do it for the same disease,
very few of them give such an option  You
can get your amount back any number of times within a year. There is
a similar point which we call NC also i.e.
No Claim Bonus for example if
you have a policy of Rs. 5 lakhs and do
not make any claim in your first year then 20%
or 50% of it depending on the insurance company will be
added to your insurance cover next year.
So what does the company say, if you do
not submit any claim in the first year then
you will be charged 20 percent, if you do not do it in the second year then you will be charged 30
percent, if you do not do it in the third year then you will be given
a cotton toe wipe. So it is possible that if
you do not make any claim for four years then
your no claim bonus is
100 percent as per your understanding. At
night the cover may increase from Rs. 500 to Rs. 10
lakhs and one very important and surprising thing is that it is
called
pre-existing disease. You have to pay attention to this
and that is why the important
point is that you should tell your insurance company
what diseases you have. Now
it is better  You should ask him to
check your health only then no disease is left out
so that when you finally do the policy,
you will have the helpline number of the company
which will know what disease you had at the
time and they do it very well
that after how many years they
cover it, but many times what the company does is that
you did
not tell us at the time of policy that you have heart
disease or diabetes, hence they do
not approve your claim, so better
show all these diseases and ask him to get
your physical checkup done, medical checkup,
keep the record with you, the next point is
that free and post hospital expenses, that is,
whenever you are on it,
your doctor's visit before that, Jio 4G
SIM addition or post discharge
expenses, how many days' note are they
covering completely, normally 30-day
test preparation and sister definition are
completely covered, you should know this point, the
next point is which company is
giving you OPD facility, that is, you
OPD charges, if you
visit a doctor without getting hospitalized and
get medicine, then it is not covered.
Another thing to repair this is that
in our country there is Indian Law for Small.
What they want is that we should
get minimum money for everything, so people with a jealous mind go
there, what some people do is that
many times they are working in the city
but their parental home is in the village, that is why they
show the address of the village
because it is cheaper for them in that area,
but if the answer is sliced ​​then
you will face problem where you are working,
companies click on it, it does
not approve it completely because the company has
decided in your body space that
your address is of that city and the
medical expenses there are 20% less, so
when you live in the policy and the people there are
working and you have to
improve your parents, then take the paint
cleaning, it will reach Indore where you live,
this is called fashionable end
Customer what happened in this case was that a
man got hospitalized then his claim
came comfortably for 1.5 lakh in the hospital, they
started filing against them
because they told that
his statement expense from other hospitals in the city is 1.5 lakh,
Bloody Mary explained that it is 5 lakh, so we
will do the empty Everest, so you should
check this claim once, verify it, ask Amazon whether
it is closed or not, we have done six and a half
inch points about health insurance, what all did
we have to check first,
but the first point to be done is
that you should tell your list with your family replacement,
how much amount you have to pay,
which city you have to take it in, how many
numbers you have to call and the best thing is that
you should put your department on any website,
their sales person is urgent, they will
call you in the morning, ask them question after question,
then you take a format from them, then the
pose of the other company will have to work a little on it, you will have to spend
time,
play 2 or 3 complete rooms  If you
do this with any of these companies, then you should
go to the team of proven companies and find out what is
born in your body, what are you
paying for and when, how much will you get for the claim,
nowadays some new companies have
come in the market which are giving you this at six and this,
but why do companies do this because
they have to build their customer base, so it is
possible that in the coming time they may make the rates
expensive and increase their influence, so do
not go for such offers, the companies which are already
in the market have made their identity,
before them you have got full customer
support from us, this is our second
video of the year, we had told you in the previous video
that when you face problem in getting a claim, then
you have to
raise your voice for your love here, today I told you
what are the check points you should do and on this day itself,
I request you to check
your balance sheet before water
and that your investment goals should be met,
if you have any doubts about any
policy, for any body system, for any
stars, then now comment
us  Before leaving, I will add you one
point, there is a class of people in our India
who should
not invest in health insurance and who are they,
who are working class and their salary is Rs. 10, so
they need health education, if you
know why, comment, we will
mix it in our next video, we will
meet again in the next video, till then keep
watching, keep listening, thank you,
like the video and subscribe to the channel and
press the bell icon and click